In this series, I'm gonna surprise you
在这一期节目中 我将给你们惊喜
and strip away all the complexity and hard gruff
抛弃所有复杂的程序 和脏话
and teach you how to make amazing food stunning on your head
然后教你们做出令你叹为观止的 美味佳肴
That is amazing. Incredibly tender.
这真是美妙 无比鲜嫩
From a kitchen novice to a betterly chef
不管你是厨房新手还是好一点的厨师
I'll give you the confidence and recipes
我将予以你自信和私家食谱
and insider knowledge to make you a much better cook
还有能让你摇身一变的内行学问
Slice around, wasting nothing.
绕着切 一点都不浪费
I've been cooking in professional kitchens for over 25 years
我已经在专业后厨工作过25年了
What is it in the macaroni lamb
这通心粉羊肉里都有什么
I've been taught by some of the best chefs in the world
我受教于一些世界顶尖大厨
And in turn, I've taught some of the best.
作为回报 我也教出过优秀的大厨
-How much whisky is in there? -A little bit.
-你放了多少威士忌?  -就一点
Now I'm gonna show you some simple and accessible recipes
现在我要向你展示一些你在家就可以做的
for fantastic food that you can easily cook at home
简单而又好把握的美食食谱
Eh, incredible
真香
I'll be holding you by the hand
我会手把手教你
It's getting better and better and better
它正变得越来越好
teaching you everything, from how to cook with chili and spice
从怎样用辣椒和香料
to bacon, real fast food and my ultimate feast recipes.
到培根 真的"快"餐 还有我的终极盛宴
This is the only cookery course you'll ever need.
这是你唯一需要的烹饪教程
S01E01 Getting Started
拉姆齐的终极烹饪教程
MurielOlala
听写制作
Welcome to my ultimate cookery course
欢迎来到我的终极烹饪课程
I have cooking tips and information
我有烹调小贴士和一些资料
and 100 recipes to stake your life on
还有100个值得你押上性命的食谱
The frying-pan is one of your best friends.
煎锅是你的好帮手
It's so versatile in the kitchen.
它在厨房就是万能的
Learning to use it with these is a must.
学会用好煎锅是一门必修课
And I'm gonna show you how.
我现在就将展示给你
First up, my delicious pan fried pork chops with sweet sour peppers.
首先 美味的甜椒煎猪扒
Whether it's in a restaurant or you at home,
不管在餐馆还是在家
one of my golden rules of producing fantastic food
我制作美食的一条黄金定律是
is learning to cook with confidence.
自信地下厨
This recipe is so straightforward,
这道菜非常简单
but taste absolutely amazing.
但尝起来绝对美味
Cook With Confidence
自信地下厨
Pan on. Get it nice and hot.
放上锅 烧热
You think of the sort of density of a pork chop
一想到猪扒那么结实
Sweet sour peppers, grow brilliantly well
熟得非常好的甜椒
how we need is a little bit of help
我们就需要一些甜椒的帮助
First, slice the peppers.
首先 切菜
That's the flat side of pepper.
这是甜椒平的一面
So stand it up.
把它立起来
Try to slide the pepper
要想从侧边
on the side is a nightmare.
滑动甜椒就是个噩梦
There's the center
找到中心
Start off
下刀
It's almost like sort of peeling an orange
这有点像拨橙子
Go a way round, and down
沿着边切下来
And look, this one
看就剩了个心
Now place the pepper down
下面把它放平
Three finger rule:
三指法则:
One finger front, two behind
一个手指在前  两个手指在后
Pinky hold it down,
小拇指把它压下来
Thumb hold it nice and flat
大拇指压平
The flatter the vegetables,
蔬菜越平
the more confident you are When you slice
你切起来就更有自信
So, don't worry about the speed.
不要担心速度
Just let the knife do the work.
就让刀子动
And take your time
慢慢来
Speed comes
速度自然就上来了
Most important thing is to get your technique right
最重要的还是把握好手法
Red onion
洋葱
Now, sweet sour peppers,
和甜椒放一起
Olive oil in,
倒入橄榄油
I'm going to saute them
我现在要小炒一下
which is just for chef terms for shallow frying
就是大厨说的嫩煎
on a high heat for maximum taste
用少油旺火快速翻炒以达到最好
Some salt and pepper
来点盐和胡椒
Add a table spoon of sugar
加一勺精白砂糖
Sugar helps to break down the peppers quicker
糖可以解辣提鲜
and caramelize the onions
给洋葱上色
Five minutes on frying-pan
在煎锅上炒5分钟
Perfect.  This one is one of the basic central tools of many kitchens
这是很多厨房里最基本的工具了
because it  is so multi-purpose
因为它真的是多用途
great for sauteing, tossing
可以快炒 翻一个
great for cooking fish and meat
也可以做鱼和肉
Push away and pull back push away and pull back
来回翻炒
That hissing is something you need to hear constantly because
你要一直听到那个滋滋声
The minute that's gone, your peppers and your onions start to boil
因为一旦它消失就意味着你的菜开始沸腾了
You really really want to saute them
而你只需要炒它
And now you start to see
现在你可以看见
and listening to the way it sound
并听到糖在熔化
caramelized, sugar is working beautifully
糖在完美地发挥作用
That's ready, for red wine vinegar
好了  可以倒上红葡萄酒醋
in, smells incredible
倒三勺
It helps to sustain the peppers as well
它也可以维持甜椒的原有味道
look at the glaze now,
看看这颜色
and you see the sugar
你能看到糖
it's work is magic
的神奇作用
Turn down the gas, and add a couple table spoon of fresh extra virgin olive oil
关小火  加两勺新鲜的特级初榨橄榄油
Then let them stew for two to three minutes
然后焖两三分钟
Now one might be peppers nice and light and sweet by a magic
下面有一样宝贝可以让甜椒更清淡和香甜
Just roll the basil
只要卷起罗勒
almost like a big cigar
像一个大雪茄一样
Slice
切碎
Basil in
放入罗勒
And then later you cook it out for 30 seconds
然后再等个半分钟
And then off
关火(因为罗勒受热味道易分解 故一般加热时间较短 百里香则需要长时间加热才出味)
beautiful!
美!
OK, pan back on
再把锅放回去
And add the pork chops
下面加猪扒
You want to make sure they don't curl up in the pan
要想让肉不在锅里蜷起来
They start curling up in a pan
肉只在加热不均匀时
when they are cooked unevenly
在锅里缩起来
A few simple cut through the rind
只需要在猪皮切透几刀
makes the chop stay flat and cooked evenly
就可以让猪扒平躺在锅里
Point the knife down
刀尖朝下
Slit through
切开缝
And then season it beautifully
然后进行调味
Nice large shards of pepper
大颗粒的碎胡椒
Punch that through lightly
轻轻用拳头捶进去
down till that seasoning
直到调好
It's gonna stay there
就让它待那
Hot pan, a touch of garlic and a touch of thyme
热锅  加一点大蒜和百里香
The garlic, take a couple of cloves
取两瓣蒜
don't peel it, don't chop it
不剥开  也不切碎
Just knife on, crush it
就用刀背拍
Olive oil in
倒入橄榄油
Just start to smoke
在刚冒烟的时候
Top of the chop, in
拿着排骨的一头
Lay away from you
在你远处放平
nice
好的
You get that heat of the pan,
你感受到锅的热度
the garlic in there early
先放蒜瓣
a nice fragrant bunch of thyme
加一小把百里香
See how the pork has stayed nice and flat
看猪排在锅上是多么的平
Turn that over, over there. Beautiful
翻过来  不错
I want a little bit of thyme underneath there
让猪排压住百里香
Start squeezing that garlic, I want all the flavor coming out
挤一挤大蒜  让它出味
Butter in
放入黄油
Thin slices of butter
薄薄的切片
ladle the pan and baste
斜一下锅  然后浇汁
So I'm sort of speeding up the cooking process
我要加快一点
at the same time, I'm keeping the pork chop really nice and moist
同时要保持猪排湿润
And another look at the butter
再看一眼黄油
Looks almost like, sort of, a light brown
差不多是浅棕色
Turn that color on another side, beautiful
把上色的一面翻过来  不错
When that fake, 3.5-4 minutes on each side
两面各烤过四分钟左右后
Let me take this from now and immediately
让我现在马上把它拿出来
So I'm gonna take them out, and let them rest
现在拿出来晾一晾
The secret of properly moist pork chops
让猪排保持适当的湿度的小秘诀是
is let them rest almost as long as they are cooked in the pan
让它晾的时间和在锅里煎的时间一样长
A nice spoon of these peppers
放一勺甜椒
basil smells incredible
罗勒闻起来真香
Put the garlic on there
把大蒜放上
Be generous with that vinegary peppers
不要吝惜这些酸酸的甜椒
because it really is incredible
因为它真的好美味
Do two things simple
只要做两件简单的事
like that, pork and peppers
就像这样  做好猪排和甜椒
And your confidence is gonna shoot for the roof
你的信心就会爆棚
A stunning pork chop
一份美味的猪扒
With sweet sour peppers
和酸甜柿子椒
The frying-pan is so simple
煎锅是那么的简单
but incredibly useful
但是无比实用
With this one pan, you can make a million different dishes
只要这一口锅  你可以做出成千上万不同的菜品
The more you cook with the frying-pan,
你用平底锅做的越多
the more your confidence will grow
你的自信就会越多
Here are three of my favorite easy pan-fried dishes
下面是三样我最喜欢的简单的煎菜
First up "pan fried scallops with crunchy apple salad"
第一道是  煎扇贝配嘎吱嘎吱苹果沙拉
Get a frying-pan smoking hot
给锅加热到冒烟
It's essential, to get quick pan frying
对于快煎来说非常重要
Add olive oil
加橄榄油
Then season scallops with salt and pepper
用盐和胡椒给扇贝调味
Starting up from the top
从锅的最前端开始放
put clockwise into the pan
把扇贝顺时针放入锅里
So you know which one to turn first
这样你就知道该先翻哪个了
Scallops have firm white sweet flesh
扇贝有着白白的结实的香肉
and cooked in minutes
只需几分钟就可以熟透
Next, salad
下一步做沙拉
Limes, lettuce, mashed popato, apple
青柠  生菜   土豆泥  苹果
Seasoning
调味
Lemon zest and juice
擦些柠檬皮  还有柠檬汁
Add olive oil, then toss
放入橄榄油  揉一揉
Turn the scallops when golden
扇贝煎成金色时翻面
Go in clockwise around the pan
沿着锅顺时针翻一圈
And squeeze in lemon juice, and give the pan a shake
挤进柠檬汁  然后晃一晃锅
Finish with lemon's zest
用柠檬皮收尾
Ready, and in under ten minutes
不到10分钟就做好了
and my first pan fried dish
我的第一道煎菜
"Scallops with Cruchy Apple Salad"
煎扇贝配嘎吱嘎吱苹果沙拉
My next super simple pan fried recipe is
下面一道超级简单的菜是
"Chicken & Chicory in Marsala Sauce"
菊苣鸡肉陪马萨拉酱
Season the chicken breast
给鸡胸肉调味
Add to hot olive oil
放入热油中
Skin side down
鸡皮一面朝下
Lay away from you, to stop all the splashing
放到离你远一点的地方  以防被溅到
Slice chicory
切菊苣
This versatile vegetable can be read all-wise
这种蔬菜可谓百搭
Have a lovely bitter taste
有一点点苦的味道
and it's great cooked or raw
不管生吃熟吃都很美味
Crush a clove of garlic and add
拍一瓣大蒜  放进去
Then sprigs of thyme
加几小枝百里香
When the chicken skin is crisp
当鸡皮变的酥脆时
Turn over
翻面
Along with the chicory
把菜也翻一下
Put the sauce, add marsala, a sweet fortify wine from Sicili
放入酱汁  加马萨拉酒  一种来自西西里的蒸馏酒
Then 150mL of chicken stock
还有150毫升的鸡汤
To make the sauce rich and droolsy
为了让酱汁更醇厚
add butter and steam for ten minuts
加入黄油  并蒸十分钟
Plate up and spoon over the sauce
装盘  淋汁
Cooked in under twenty minutes
20分钟以内就做好了
"Chicken & Chicory in Marsala Sauce"
菊苣鸡肉陪马萨拉酱
My final dish cooked in versatile frying-pan is:
我用万能平底锅介绍的最后一道菜是
"Sea bream with tomato and herb salsa"
鲷鱼配西红柿香草酱
fry the fillets of sea bream skin side down, in hot olive oil
将鲷鱼片鱼皮一面朝下放入热油中
If it buckle up, press gently down
如果它鼓起来就轻轻压下去
For perfect even cooking
以达到均匀加热的目的
Then season
调味
Sea bream has firm white flesh, perfect for pan fry
鲷鱼白嫩鲜美  适合煎熟
Next the salsa,
下面做酱
Heat olive oil
加热橄榄油
Add half cherry tomatoes, pitted black olives
加切半的小西红柿  还有去核的黑橄榄
and season
调味
After a minute, on a low heat
一分钟后  用微火
add coriander, basil and lemon
放入香菜  罗勒  和柠檬
Combine and leave it in fuse
放到一边
As the sea bream cooks, it goes opaque
当鲷鱼加热时  它逐渐不透明起来
When it's 2/3 from the top, turn over
当有三分之二不透明时  翻面
Baste, fry, and it's done.
淋汁  再煎一会就可以出锅了
"Sea Bream with Tomato Herbs Salsa"
鲷鱼配西红柿香草酱
ready in under fifteen minutes
15分钟就做好了
One pan, three simple, impressive and absolutely delicious dishes
只要一个锅就可以做出三道美味
Beautiful!
真棒
Coming up on my ultimate cookery course
接下来
along with 100 recipes to stake your life on
和这100道菜品一起
I would give you 100 quick cooking tips
我将给你100条厨房小贴士
to make your life in the kitchen easier
使你的厨房生活更轻松
First up, how to keep your knife sharp
首先  怎样保持刀子锋利
It's far harder working in the kitchen
在厨房用一把钝刀
with a blunt knife than it is with a sharp knife
比用一把锋利的刀子要困难很多
The secret behind keeping a sharp knife:
保持刀子锋利的秘诀是
Sharpen it before every time you use it
每一次用之前都先磨一下
First grip the steel
首先握住磨刀钢的手柄
If you are really uncomfortable about holding a steel
如果你觉得拿着磨刀钢不舒服的话
imagine you are holding a tennis racket
可以想象你是拿着网球拍
or you are playing squash,
或者在打壁球
God, you are really comfortable with this
你会觉得非常舒服
Now, 45 degrees, confident grip
倾斜45度  自信的抓着
confident grip of knife
握好刀
This is the butt of the steel
这是磨刀棒的末端
really important to keep your fingers behind that
一定要把手指放在后面
you never grip a steel with your fingers over that
千万不要把手指放到前面去
'Cause when your knife comes back in you just lost a finger
因为当刀收回来时你就丢了根手指
always grip behind
一定要握在后面
Nice long strokes, so we got whole of the blade over steel
长长的划过去  这样可以让整个刀锋划过磨刀棒
stroke, and we start from the bottom to the top
划过去  从后至前
So there, across, stroke, stroke
像这样  划呀划
over the top of the steel
直到磨刀棒的顶部
Then come back underneath
再划回来
It's so dangerous working in the kitchen with a blunt knife
用一把钝的刀是很危险的
can cause so much damage
会造成很大伤害
Working with a sharp knife is ten times quicker, more efficient
用快刀不仅会更快  还会更有效率
now, that's ready to start chopping
现在可以切菜了
To stop your chopping board rocking or slipping,
要让你的切菜板不晃不滑
a great tip is simplyto wet a kitchen cloth, kitchen paper
一个好方法就是润湿抹布
or tea towel
或者茶巾
and place it underneath
垫在下面
now you can chop with confidence
这样你就可以信心十足地切菜了
My next top tip is
第三条贴士是
Get the most out of your humble vege paner
尽可能地利用削皮器
It's brilliant for slicing ultra thin ribbons of edge,
它可以削条
perfect for asian dishes
十分适合亚洲菜
Great for making long delicate pumps and shavings
也很适合细致地刮花
to top soups and salad
放在汤和沙拉里
It also makes wonderful chocolate curls
它也可以刮巧克力
Your pepper mill is more versatile than you might think
你的胡椒瓶也比你想象的更神奇
tighten the top screw to get finely ground pepper
把上端拧紧可以得到细胡椒粉
ideal for soups and sauces
十分适合汤和酱汁
for general seasoning, you'd want it medium ground
对于一般的调味  可以用中等研磨
So set the screw in the middle
就拧在中间
And loosen it right off for coarse pepper
全放松可以得到粗胡椒
perfect for steaks and fish
适合牛排和鱼
Peeling Garlic
剥大蒜
One clove, simply bash it with the back of the knife
取一瓣  只需要用刀拍开
and the skin comes off easily
皮自然就掉了
For a whole head, crush separate into a bowl
对于一整头蒜  用手压开  分开放碗里
cover and shake hard for about ten seconds
盖上盖  使劲摇一会
and simply pick out the peeled cloves
然后拣出来没有皮的蒜瓣
Coming up on my ultimate cookery course
接下来
more great cooking tips
更多贴士
hold it down, your fingers on there
用手指压住
really nice way of taking off all those nice
可以把那些香嫩的百里香
fragrant of little thyme flowers
剥下来
how to shop for the best ingredients
怎样买到最好的原料
For skin in nice white color
鸡皮是漂亮的白色
with the smell of fresh chickeny smell
有一种新鲜的鸡的味道
And a stunning roast chicken recipe to stake your life on
还有一道值得你押上性命完美的烤鸡食谱
Incredible
真好
This is my ultimate cookery course
这是我的终极烹饪教程
100 recipes to stake your life on
100道价值连城的美食
I'll be showing you a roast chicken recipe to die for
下面这道烤鸡一定会是你的最爱
Hold the drum, to slice straight through
拿住小腿  直接切开
But first, like any good chef,
但首先  像每一位好大厨
I'm always looking to get great ingredients at the right price
总要找到最好的材料
my shopping mentor is simple
我的购物原则非常简单
First, is relying on your senses
第一是相信你的感觉
make sure whatever you buy, it looks smells, and really feels good
不管买什么  它闻起来感觉起来一定要都很好
If you get the chance, taste it before you buy it
如果有机会  在买之前尝一下
Second is to recognise that knowledge is crucial
第二是认识到专业知识非常重要
The more you know about where your ingredients come from
关于你的原材料你知道的越多
and how they are produced, the better
越容易做出一道好菜
So, ask a lot of questions and learn
所以  要多问多学
You are never too old to learn from an expert
向专家学习知识从来不晚
and when it comes to buy a great bird,
当你要买禽类时
one person knows what to look for,
有一人知道你要什么
is award-winning, fifth generation master butcher Danny Lidgate
就是获奖众多的第五代屠夫传人  丹尼 李德格
Poultry is a great meat
禽类是种好肉
because there's many different types of birds that is worth tasting
因为有那么多值得一尝的鸟类
Their variation of flavors between  the two different birds is massive
两种鸟的味道是决然不同的
Turkey is a great lean meat
火鸡是一种非常棒的瘦肉
because it's available all year round
全年都可以吃到
not just for christmas
不仅仅是圣诞节
and anybody who's worried about eating fatty meats
对于那些担心吃到肥肉的人们来说
it's a really healthy, flavorsome meal
火鸡又健康又香
Gamebirds
野鸡
People never try them well enough
人们绝对吃不够
Once they are shot, they'll hang up for a little while
猎到以后  要把他们晾起来
a few days at least
至少要两三天
and these meat is gonna be more tender
肉就会变得嫩很多
all add flavors to the birds
并给肉添进风味
I've got a woodpigeon
我现在手里拿的是林鸽
and a red-legged partridge
和一只红腿鹧鸪
both really good, and cooked really quickly
都非常好  很容易熟
When you're buying a chicken,
当你买鸡时
some of things to look careful
一定要注意
is always the smell
它的味道
And when you're smelling a good quality chicken,
当你在闻一只好鸡时
you can tell the difference
你可以闻出区别
It's skin is in nice white color
它的皮是好看的白色
And it smells like a fresh chickeny smell
有一种新鲜的鸡肉味
When you buy it from a good bird shop
如果你从一家好店买
you'll find that you can get the giblets as well
你也能得到鸡杂
which is basically the neck and other organs
主要是脖子和内脏
this is great for making gravy
十分适合做肉酱
once your are to cook you can use all you've got and other things
当你要做时 你可以用到所有部分
stir fries, curries, pasta dishes
炒啦  咖喱啦  意面啦
save the bones, use the bones for stocks and soups
留下骨头  用骨头熬鸡汤
it really pack full of the flavor
真是满是香味
And remember, there are lots of different breeds of chicken
一定要记得  这么多种鸡
All have varied characteristics and flavors
每一个都有不同的特点和味道
So, shop around and find the one that you love
到处看看  总能挑到你最喜欢的
Here are three of my all-time favorites
下面是我一直喜欢的三样最爱
These come from an old British breed
它来自古英国的一种
They've got smaller breast, but the meat is delicious
胸比较小  但肉非常好吃
a fantastich French variety
它来自法国
suck in with bags of flavor
可以吸收各种味道
and really meaty thighs
还有多肉的大腿
this is the rolls royce of the chicken
这是一种劳斯莱斯级的鸡
rich, gamy and delicious
肥  很强的味道  超级美味
One for special occasions
适合特殊场合
I think people should maybe try and buy
我认为大家不应该在意肉的多少
less meat but aim for the best quality
而关注最好的质量
You'll only get out when you put in
买什么吃什么
When you put the best quality into the dish,
只有买最好的鸡
you're gonna get best results
才能做出最好的菜
No matter how season a chef you are
不管大厨处于哪个阶段
There are always new ingredients and recipes to get find up about
但四季都有令人心动的新的材料和食谱
So if you are tired of all recipes getting you down
所以如果旧的食谱做烦了
Spice it up, with fresh ideas and flavors
就用新鲜的想法来添点味道吧
My next recipe is an old classic roast chicken,
我的下一道菜是一道经典的烤鸡
but with a simple twist, it tastes on a new life
但只需要变一点  尝起来就是一种新的感觉
and it's guaranteed to imipress
保证让你放不下碗
One of the things I love about cooking
能让我一直热爱烹饪
and keep me excited up to 25 years behind the stove
并且在厨房保持激情25年的原因之一
is that there's always something new to learn everyday
就是每一天总有新的东西可学
new ingredients, new techniques and new cuisines
新的食材  新的方法  还有新的烹饪
Get Excited
保持激情
Start off with the stuffing
从填料开始
It's amazing how exciting a stuffed  roast chicken can be
带馅烤鸡是非常神奇的
because it keeps the chicken incredibly moist
因为它可以让鸡保持湿度
and gives a delicious texture inside the bird
并给鸡一种美妙的质感
we start off with cured chorizo
首先  熏制的西班牙香肠
this is a traditional Spanish sausage
这是一种传统的西班牙香肠
and it's garlicy, spicy and incredibly meaty
有蒜香  有点辣  非常结实
that gives a little bit the sort of richness to the stuffing
给馅料一种丰满度
get the chorizo in
放入香肠
start cooking that down and you get all those oils out
可以把它的油放出来
a touch of olive oil in there to get it gooey
放一点橄榄油  让它粘一点
right, onions
好了  洋葱
chops
切碎
add the onions to the chorizo
倒进锅里
and at the matter of seconds,
只需几秒
they'll change color as they soak up all the flavor
洋葱就会变色 吸收进所有的味道
That lovely spicinesses being stolen from that sausage
吸收掉香肠的辣味
now the onions smell incredible
现在洋葱闻起来超棒
Garlic
大蒜
Garlic in
放进去
Fresh thyme
新鲜的百里香
and just hold it down and the fingers on there
握在手里  用手指把住
it's a really nice way of taking off all those fragrant little thyme flowers
这样就可以更快的让百里香发挥出来
you hear the cracking in the background
你听到爆破声没
These are cannellini beans
这是意大利白豆
they're waxy, very soft
白色的  软软的
they're so delicious but very dense
非常美味
but so for stuffing, they're so robust
对馅来说非常强健
nothing breaks down
怎样都混不了味
drain them off
排掉水
in
放进去
they're gonna take all out the juice as well from the chorizo
它也将拽出香肠的味道
it needs season now
调味
because it's very dense so it needs a litle bit help
因为它很的稠密感需要一点改变
now it looks like it's a dish on its own
现在看起来就像一道菜一样
and good enough to eat now
已经可以吃了
I want to sweet things up a little bit
我要加一点甜度
tomatoes, half dried, in
把半干的西红柿加进去
let the sweetness up
让它甜一点
the stuffing...
这馅料...
beautiful
真好
The stuff is ready
馅料可以了
look at the color and every thing
看它的颜色还有别的
The spanish, it looks delicious
这香肠看起来真好吃
now, stuff it in the chicken
把它填到鸡肚子里
I like taking off these, the knuckles
我要拿掉鸡爪子
As the chicken cooks
随着鸡烤熟
the skin stretches over the bone and you get a really nice drum
它的皮会抻开包住骨头  得到一只完美的琵琶骨
And take off these little wing tips as well
把这些翅尖也拿下来
Salt and pepper
盐和胡椒调味
So important
非常重要
now, your stuffing i'll go right inside of the chicken
现在把你的馅填进去
push it down
摁下去
this really helps to cook the bird evenly
这样可以烤得更均匀
Because you are pushing out all the empty spaces in the carcass
因为同时你在挤出空气
and take a nice large lemon
然后拿一个大柠檬
push the lemon in
推进去
pick up the parson's nose
揪起鸡屁股
pull the skin over
把鸡皮摁在一起
Olive oil on top
在上面浇上橄榄油
salt and pepper
盐和胡椒
a teaspoon of paprika
加一勺辣椒粉
sprinkle it on
撒在上面
and then your hands sort of rub that in
然后用手抹一遍
and you see what paprika's doing to the chicken
可以看到这辣椒粉
it's like sweet, spicy marinade
好像甜辣卤汁一样
as though you've roasted it, but it looks delicious
好像已经烤过一样
400ml of white wine, same quantity of water
400毫升白葡萄酒和等量的水
That helps the chicken to steam
可以保证烤盘内有充足的水分
chicken in
把鸡放进去
be generous with the thymes sprigs
多放一点百里香
make sure the foil is foiled tightly around the roasting tray
要保证锡纸在烤盘边上裹得非常严实
so the chicken steams in the oven keep it moist and juicy
这样鸡肉才能在烤盘内保持湿润多汁
into the oven
放入烤箱
cook it for an hour at 180 degrees with the foil on
在180度下烤一小时
take it out and remove the foil lid
之后拿出烤盘  揭掉锡纸
and give it another 30 minutes to crispen that skin
再放入烤箱烤30分钟让鸡皮更酥脆
so important to make sure you take that tin foil off
一定要把锡纸揭掉
with half an hour to go
再烤半小时
beautiful
非常棒
Pierce that open
把柠檬刺开
squeeze it in that delicious gravy
把柠檬汁挤进肉酱里
mix that into the tray
在烤盘里搅一搅
and sieve that
用筛子过滤一下
that's really nice, fragrant, lemony, spiced roasting juices to finish
用非常香带着柠檬香带着辣味的烧烤汁收尾
Before you cut up the chicken
在切开之前
take out the amazing stuffing
先把馅取出来
incredible
真好
I would have that with chicken and potatoes anyday
任何一天我都会想配着土豆吃
and then just get your ckicken roasting juices
然后浇上你的烧烤鸡汁
now, to cut the chicken up
现在把鸡肉切开
hold the drum, and slice straight through
拿着小腿  直直地切开
There's that, a wonderful drum and thigh
就这样 完美的琵琶腿和鸡大腿
through the wishbone, off
沿着叉骨  切开
slice with the point and an angle
以一定角度把鸡肉切成片
so you see the texture of that amzing roast chicken
你能看到烤鸡的纹理
let's take the cooking juices
拿起烧烤汁
work carefully with that sort of lemony flavor over my chicken
带着柠檬的味道浇在鸡肉上
and there you go
好了
a delicious, very charming, stuffed roast chicken
一道美味可口的带馅烤鸡
Follow my ultimate cookery course, crammed with key lessons
跟随着我满是重要课程
top tips and 100 recipes to stake your life on
和私家秘诀  以及100道美食的终极烹饪教程
and you'll literally be cooking yourself into a better chef
你一定会变成一个更好的厨师
took a look at my selected recipes from my show
你可以在网上看到我节目里的精选菜肴
go to my scrapbook @channel4.com/gordon
网址是 channel4.com/gordon
go on, get cooking!
加油  下厨吧
next time
下集预告
my ultimate guide to keep it simple,
我的终极指导  保持简洁
chili beef lettuce wraps, so easy that you can cook them by heart
一道好菜  生菜卷辣牛肉  简单的你都可以背过
smells amazing
闻起来真香
one knife to buy," feeling the grip and better the chopping"
一把好刀  "感受它的把就能切地更好"
and more essential shopping tips
以及更多购物秘诀
smell it before, get your nose right into it
先用鼻子闻  把鼻子埋进去
don't go like that, get into it, smell it
不要离那么远  埋进去  使劲闻
如有疏漏 恳请指正
如有疏漏 恳请指正
诚邀同好共同制作@Gagagaga要做数学家
诚邀同好共同制作@Gagagaga要做数学家